

## **JOE SWARBRICK**

**DIGITAL MEDIA & FRONT END WEB DEVELOPEMENT** 

### CONTACT



joe@swarbs.co.uk



07717726494

## **DOMAIN**



Swarbs.co.uk

### **SKILLSET**

HTML5 & CSS3

Javascript & JQuery

PHP

WordPress Development

Shopify & Liquid

Sass & SCSS

Visual Studio

Xampp

Notepad++

## **SUMMARY**

Confident, outgoing front-end developer who delights in working on user interfaces to implement the best possible end user experience.

5+ years' experience working with various CMS and E-Commerce platforms (WordPress, WooCommerce, Shopify and Joomla).

Always looking to learn wherever possible and pickup new languages and syntaxes to broaden my skillset, with designs on becoming a fullstack developer.

## **WORK HISTORY**

**Little Secrets Clothing - Designer:** Feb 2020 - Present day **Key responsibilities:** 

- Primarily responsible for making designs to fulfill orders
- Creating new vinyl designs,
- Designing graphics for web
- Web maintenance (Shopfiy) Creating and adding new sections and editing with custom code if necessary
- Overseeing the implementation and customization of a new theme managing apps and improving site speed wherever possible

The Bay Horse Inn, Roughlee - Manager and Director:

Nov 2017 - Oct 2021

### **Key responsibilities:**

- Running the pub and overseeing day-to-day service
- Managing both front of house and kitchen staff at all levels
- Various administrative duties across all areas of the business, including paying staff and suppliers/rent/rates

Basic knowledge of Rest API

In-depth knowledge of Adobe CC 2021

Working on Windows, Linux and Mac

**GIMP 2.0** 

Inkscape

### **EDUCATION**

#### **DEGREE:**

BSc (hons) Digital Media and Technologies from Bradford University

#### **A-LEVELS:**

Fine art, Geology, Biology

# PERSONAL STENGTHS

Teamwork

Time management

Communication

Work ethic

Managing staff

Personability

Customer interaction

- Producing and maintaining a website (built in WordPress)
- Producing graphics for print and social media
- Various IT maintenance

## The fabl - Digital Manager: Dec 2016 - June 2018 Key responsibilities:

- <u>Developing new WordPress sites or overhauling existing ones in tandem with the design team</u>
- Developing and maintaining the company site thefabl.com
- Constantly working to improve the UI and UX for Toolally.com (sister company)
- Assisting the design team in creating various web-suitable media
- Assisting a 3<sup>rd</sup> party app development team in linking Toolally website and database with app via REST API
- Various web maintenance for clients including installing SSL certificates
- Setting up and maintaining VPS hosting

## **SA Graphics – Web Marketing Assistant**: Sept 2016 – Dec 2016 **Key responsibilities**:

- Creating written content on behalf of clients to be posted on their websites
- Checking and maintaining the security of client's websites using apps and plugins
- Assisting with styling and UI

## **Assistant Manager - The Bull at Broughton**: Jun 2015 - Sept 2016. **Key responsibilities**:

- Assisting in the day-to-day running of the business
- Replying to Google and TripAdvisor reviews
- Placing orders from suppliers
- Managing staff

#### The Three Fishes - Junior Manager: Apr 2015 - June 2015.

- Assisting in the day-to-day running of the business
- Assisting in purchasing and maintenance of stock
- Managing staff

The Three Fishes - Part Time FOH Assistant: 2010 - 2015.